One Man, One Mission, One Choice
Capsule is a drama, history, science fiction film directed by Andrew Martin.
1959: Guy is an experienced British fighter pilot who is in
command of Britain's first manned mission to space.
He has trained for this for three years at the height of the Cold War and now he is
alone in space, suffering Hypoxia, with a malfunctioning capsule.
He has limited contact with the UK, some unusual communication with the US and
some unorthodox communication with Tyuratam deep in Soviet Russia.
Can he get home?
Who will help him?
Will he make the right choice?
Guy Taylor, played by Edmund Kingsley.
Charlotte Taylor, played by Lisa Greenwood.
Harry Lyndhurst, played by David Wayman.
Agent Mike Spann, played by Nigel Barber.
Graham Bennett, played by Gil Kolirin.
Bob Elijah, played by Michael Koltes.
A time capsule is a historic cache of goods or information, usually intended as a deliberate method of
communication with future people, and to help future archaeologists, anthropologists, or historians.
The preservation of holy relics dates back for millennia, but the practice of preparing and preserving a
collection of everyday artifacts and messages to the future appears to be a more recent practice.
Time capsules are sometimes created and buried during celebrations such as world's
fairs or cornerstone layings for buildings or at other ceremonies.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, spy, deception, alone, space.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.